SURYA RYALI

235 queens road, Leicester, LCE LE2 3FP

07825160147

suryaryali249@gmail.com

Professional Summary

A motivated and active professional with data analysis skills. demonstrated 2+ years of experience in the industry and dedication to deliver top results. A team player who generates a motivated attitude and a variety of experiences with productive processes and tools. I am always striving to use my professional skills to add value to an organization's mission, including exceptional knowledge of the sector along with excellent operations, business, and time management skills.

WORK HISTORY

Data Analyst, 03/2023 - Current

ROHLIG Logistics

- Deep understanding of Supply Chain Systems, including Control towers and connected
- Monitored and reported on key performance indicators (KPIs) using dashboards for various stakeholders
- Implemented data workflows to streamline automated Power BI and Databricks input.
- Conducted thorough requirements gathering across operations to identify pain points and areas for improvement in existing processes and systems Scoped
- Highlighted process improvement opportunities to streamline database management and analysis.
- Cleansed and ordered data to maintain efficient warehousing operations.
- Optimized supply chain operations by implementing lean principles with data analysis and reducing department costs.

Data Analyst, 10/2022 - 01/2023

University of Leicester - Leicester

- Conducted in-depth analysis of customer's responses to interest rate fluctuations for loans
- Examining their impact on deposit behavior and providing valuable insights by using large datasets
- Deposit data, identifying patterns, trends, and correlations for optimizing deposit strategies.
- I applied extensive industry knowledge in financial services, specifically banking, and investments, to inform data analysis and recommendations.
- Successfully worked with large datasets, including analyzing millions of rows of data from multiple countries and optimizing processing time using the Python libraries
- Proficiently handled and managed massive datasets for advanced analytical processes, leveraging expertise in data science tools and contributing to the entire project lifecycle.
- I am skilled in time-series analysis and predictive modelling using R and Python, specializing in addressing big data challenges such as predictive analytics and fraud
- Detection, customer segmentation, and marketing campaigns.

Data Analyst, 09/2019 - 03/2021

AMTP Software Pvt Ltd - Chennai

- Created a business intelligence solution that transforms banking data into intelligence. Leveraged Power BI tool to provide interactive
- Customer-related dashboards with rich visuals and self-service capabilities are required to empower the client's operations team.
- Developed dashboards that increased insights, interpretations, and predictions for improved forecasting.

- Developed simple as well as complex SQL queries to fetch data into the reports and to send the data extract to the various global operations within Axis Bank.
- For small and compact datasets, have developed visualization within Excel and done explorative Data Analysis(EDA)
- Allows the operations team to make intelligent decisions for efficiently managing customer 360 and finding churn rates in the bank accounts.
- Focus on all aspects of analytics for the bank, including risk analytics, financial crime analytics, business and marketing analytics, building predictive scores, data engineering, and business reporting.

SKILLS

- Proficient in MS Excel, Tableau, and Power BI
- Data Mining/Analysis, ETL
- Machine Learning and Statistical Modeling
- Data modelling, SQL, T-SQL
- Python, PySpark, and R Language
- CRM and Google analytics tools
- Azure data factory, Snowflake, Data warehousing

- Azure, AWS Cloud
- LINUX, Docker, and CI/CD Pipelines
- Good Verbal and Written skills
- Problem-solving and Hardworking
- Strong Communication skills
- Leadership skills

EDUCATION

Bachelor 's: Electrical Engineering, 04/2015 - 06/2019

University of JNTUK - INDIA

Masters of Science: Data Analysis for Business Intelligence in Distinction, 10/2021 - 02/2023

University of Leicester - Leicester, UK

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Data Analytics in Coursera Azure Dp900 Python and R from Datacamp Certified in Microsoft Power BI